Email: m.srinu.vishwanath@gmail.com Phone: +91-988-515-2072

PROFILE

Senior manager with over 15 years of hands-on experience spanning client, partner, operations, project, PMO, product and team management. A diverse background in technical and managerial areas with experience in creating vision, strategies, business management, and for delivering business critical information system projects to clients located in Asia, Middle-East and Europe.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Project Management
- Client Management
- Account Management
- Program Management
- Change Management
- BID Management
- Operations Management
- Risk Management
- Transition Management

KEY STRENGTHS

- Prioritizing
- Technical skills
- Goal Oriented

- Communication
- Interpersonal skills
- Dependability

- Multitasking
- Time Manager
- Flexible

SKILLS

- Leadership
- Process Automation
- Solutioning

- Lean/Six Sigma
- Analytics
- MIS

- PMP Trained
- Due Diligence
- Business Excellence

CERTIFICATIONS

• SCRUM MASTER

• ITIL Foundation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE / ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Serviceberry Technologies Pvt Ltd Project Manager

Projects: RBI, Bank of Baroda and Havells Ltd

Oct. 2018 - Till Date

- Coordinating interfaces between design coordination, service transition planning and reporting and other processes
- Ensuring the consistent design of appropriate services, service management information systems, architectures, technology, processes, information and metrics to meet current and evolving business outcomes and requirements
- Coordinating all design activities across projects, changes, suppliers and support teams, and managing schedules, resources and conflicts where required
- Planning and coordinating the resources and capabilities required to design new or changed services
- Ensuring that appropriate service designs and/or DFS's are produced and that they are handed over to service transition as agreed
- Managing the quality criteria, requirements and handover points between the service design stage and service strategy and service transition
- Improving the effectiveness and efficiency of service design activities and processes
- Coordinating service transition activities across projects, suppliers and service teams
- Ensuring that the final delivery of each service transition meets the agreed customer and stakeholder requirements specified in the service design package

Email: m.srinu.vishwanath@gmail.com Phone: +91-988-515-2072

FCI-CCM

Project Manager Sept. 2017 – Sept. 2018

Projects: Bank of Baroda & ICICI Bank

- Create and maintain systems best practices, addressing business, application, data, technology and templates (for letters, statements etc.) in the context of business processes across the division.
- Provide leadership direction and accountability for strategic application architecture patterns, plans, system design, and implementation.
- Collaborate with other teams, the technology delivery team and the technology infrastructure team to define architectural approaches and solutions, conduct business reviews, document current templates in the portfolio, and recommend how to proceed with the applications (replace, retire, maintain, etc.).
- Develop and tailor application design concepts and implementation plans for the efficient transformation of the current CCM application portfolio.
- Develop and maintain CCM design patterns, oversee the development of templates, migration of existing templates, and other components and oversee performance and security testing of CCM application modules (GMC Inspire, Automation, ICM, Production Formatter) and interfaces.
- Identify emerging trends, thought leadership in software development & introduce these to the project as well as the enterprise.

Intense Technologies Limited Manager, PSG Portfolio projects

April 2015 - Sept. 2017

Projects: Reliance Jio, HDFC Bank, HDFC Life, Birla Sunlife Insurance

- Responsible for Account Management, Delivery Management, People Management, Vendor/Partner Management, Client Management, TAT adherence and CSAT.
- Responsible for delivering projects against agreed scope, budget, schedule & customer expectations. Doing this whilst supervising, directing & motivating teams of multi-discipline contractors & employees.
- Monitoring project risks and scope creep to identify potential problems.
- Produce stage plans, highlight reports, risk logs, requests for change etc.
- Provide strategic direction during the implementation stages.
- Manage client expectations by ensuring the delivery of the highest quality service.
- Commercial awareness, business acumen and multi- vendor environments experience.
- Manage technical process and resolve technical issues.
- Understand and document project requirements and dependencies.
- Experience of managing change within CRM, Marketing and Finance systems.
- Work with and support cross-functional project teams.

UnitedHealth Group

Assistant Manager Operations

Oct. 2014 - April 2015

- Work with and support cross-functional project teams.
- Responsible for troubleshooting of routine computer application problems to maintain or restore service or data to programs.
- Responsible for resolving basic and moderately complex issues.
- Responsible for performing support/maintenance and/or simple modification application programming tasks, and assists with testing and debugging applications/programs.
- Responsible for updating the ticket logs, reports (IBatch Status Reports, Defect Trackers etc) wherever needed.
- Work and assist senior team members in handling scheduled/unscheduled issues like outages, defects fixing etc
- Proactively monitor the system health and alerts and assures high levels of stability, reliability, availability of production environment.
- Demonstrating understanding of BCP, quality, security and compliance requirements for supported areas.
- Participating in the US/APAC Calls/meetings with the Senior Technology Team Members or business users

Email: m.srinu.vishwanath@gmail.com Phone: +91-988-515-2072

Progressive Careers Assistant Manager Technical Support

Dec. 2011 - Oct. 2014

- · Accountable for customer experience, responsiveness, and resource productivity within component area.
- KPI attainment at component level, particularly SLA, productivity and knowledge targets.
- Identifying key drivers of SR volume and productivity issues at component level.
- Creating and executing mitigation plans.
- Ensuring consistent process compliance within component area, partnering with regional managers and quality engineers to identify and resolve gap areas.
- Partnering with Engineering and Release Readiness to ensure smooth ramp-up and knowledge transfer for new products / releases into component area.
- Product Expertise, Knowledge Management, and Product Quality.
- Maintaining personal broad knowledge of product area and deep component expertise.
- Ensuring Support Engineers build and maintain deep component expertise, leveraging formal training and knowledge
 plans.
- Ensuring completeness and quality of knowledge base for component area.
- Soliciting feedback from customers and employees about product quality and thematic support issues.
- Partnering with Engineering and Solution Architects to prioritize themes and deliver resolutions which improve the customer experience and product supportability.
- Building and maintaining alignment with managers and quality engineers across the product area to drive positive customer outcomes.
- Engaging with cross-functional teams (Customer Support, Engineering, Solutions Management, Cloud Operations, Consulting, Delivery, Partners, Commercial, etc) to support initiatives that improve the customer experience and/or goals of SAP SD.
- Ensuring each employee has measurable goals and development plans in place.
- Engaging with employees on career path plans.

HSBC Technology and Services Quality Analyst

Feb 2005 - Dec. 2011

- Successfully Re-migrated HFCA Customer Care to Manila.
- Yellow Belt Certified for reduction in time taken for processing letters.
- Successfully completed my other three time reduction projects which were delegated to my colleagues.
- Have migrated HSBC Finance Canada process which deals with Personal, Mortgage Loans and Two Wheeler loans.
- Responsible for conducting On Job Training sessions for the new batches, which includes classroom training sessions as well as sharing updates with representatives to groom them to attain floor expectations.
- Has been involved in creating the HFCA Customer Care Manual during migration.
- Being a Quality analyst, conduct conference calls and call calibrations with the agents from the Operations Floor to ensure consistency in understanding of policies and procedures.
- Monitoring calls and auditing accounts to provide feedback to the teams on Quality, Accuracy, Handle Time, Language defects and other performance metrics.
- Handle Escalations and help resolve complex customer issues by Liaoning with the various departments in the Business Area.

Email: m.srinu.vishwanath@gmail.com Phone: +91-988-515-2072

Sri Chaitanya Info Systems Pvt. Ltd.

Designation: Team Leader Sep. 2004 – Feb. 2005

- Had been a part of outbound sales for AT&T mobiles.
- Promoted as a Team Leader within a span of 3 months.
- Handled the sales targets for the team.
- Initiated incentive plan to increase the sales for the organization.

Hutch India Pvt. Ltd.

Designation: Team Leader

Jun. 2003 - Aug. 2004

- Handled a team which used to market post paid phone connections within Hyderabad.
- Need to make sure that there are profits generated by meeting the monthly set targets.
- Provided training on a timely basis to the executives.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

- Bsc Computers from Himalayan University
- Pursuing MBA-IT from University of Mumbai
- ITIL
- Scrum Master